For many time-poor, health-conscious people, the must-have kitchen gadget at the moment is an air fryer.
对于许多时间紧张、注重健康的人来说，当下厨房必备的小家电就是空气炸锅。
From top chefs to humble students, many are singing the praises of the device that seems to be flying off the shelves at shops and online.
从顶级大厨到普通学生，许多人都对这款设备赞不绝口，它在线上线下的商店里都卖得异常火爆。
One British department store reported sales increased by 400% in 2021.
英国一家百货公司报告称，2021年空气炸锅的销量涨幅高达400%。
But are they really the best thing since sliced bread, or is the hype all just hot air?!
但它们真的是继切片面包之后最棒的发明吗？还是说这场热度不过是夸夸其谈？
If you got one as a present, or bagged one in the sales, you'll already know the benefits.
如果你收到过一台空气炸锅作为礼物，或是在促销时入手了一台，那你一定已经知道它的好处。
An air fryer avoids the need to deep-fry food in hot and often unhealthy oil.
空气炸锅无需用滚烫且往往不健康的油来油炸食物。
Instead, the food is cooked by having very hot air blown on it at high speed – it doesn't actually fry but bakes the food.
相反，它是通过高速吹送热风来烹制食物——它实际上并非油炸，而是烘烤食物。
The technology sounds simple, and Dr Jakub Radzikowski, Culinary Education Designer at Imperial College London, told the BBC: "You could compare it to drying your hair with a hairdryer."
这项技术听起来十分简单，伦敦帝国理工学院的烹饪教育设计师雅各布·拉齐科夫斯基博士在接受BBC采访时表示：“你可以把它比作用吹风机吹头发。”
The combination of a powerful fan and a smaller compartment makes the air fryer more efficient and reduces the time needed to pre-heat it.
强劲的风扇和更小的腔体相结合，让空气炸锅的效率更高，还缩短了预热所需的时间。
In addition, because the food is cooked in a basket, excess fat will drip to the bottom, so you don't have to eat it.
此外，由于食物是放在炸篮中烹制的，多余的油脂会滴落到容器底部，你也就不会摄入这些油脂了。
And it's good to know air fryers use less energy than a conventional oven because of the shorter cooking times needed.
而且值得一提的是，由于烹制时间更短，空气炸锅比传统烤箱更省电。
Some people may question how versatile they are and whether they can be used for cooking whole meals.
有些人可能会质疑它们的用途是否广泛，能不能用来做一整顿饭。
But experts have prepared crispy sweet potato fries, chips, and chicken and fish, quickly and with good flavoursome results – cooked to perfection.
但专家们已经用空气炸锅快速做出了酥脆的甜薯条、炸薯块、鸡肉和鱼肉，成品味道上佳，火候恰到好处。
Dr Jakub Radzikowski's favourite is chicken legs or thighs, which he says after 20 minutes gives you something that's "perfectly juicy inside" with a skin that is so crispy it "shatters like glass".
雅各布·拉齐科夫斯基博士最爱的是用它做鸡腿或鸡大腿，他说，20分钟后，就能得到一份“内里汁水充盈”、外皮酥脆到“像玻璃一样一碰就碎”的成品。
If this whets your appetite, remember that, because of the air fryer's size, there is a limit to the amount that can be cooked in them at one time.
如果这让你心动了，要记住，受限于空气炸锅的尺寸，它一次能烹制的食物量是有限的。
So your oven may still come in handy.
所以你的烤箱可能还是能派上用场。
But if you're on a budget or in a rush, it might be worth giving one a try and seeing what amazing meals you can serve up.
但如果你预算有限，或是时间紧张，不妨试试空气炸锅，看看能做出多少惊艳的美食。